Six Sigma Deployment Planning Matrix
Welcome to this session on deployment planning.
What we’re going to look at now are ten key plans
that we need to develop to successfully rollout Six Sigma across an organization.
The first is we need a metrics plan. This metrics plan is critical.
The metrics plan is basically defining
what we’re going to measure? How we’re going to measure it? When we’re going to measure it,
at the business, operations, and process level?
We need a communications plan. How are we going to communicate with each other?
What we’re going to communicate? How we are going to communicate?
We need a budgeting plan that defines how budgeting will occur.
How much each thing will be allocated? A training plan.
Very simple. What are we going to train in? When we are going to train?
Who are we going to train? Accounting. We need an accounting plan.
Because remember, our accounting system likely will not be able to keep track
of a lot of the different costs and benefits associated with Six Sigma.
We need a goal setting plan. How do we set our goals
at the business, operation, and process level to ensure they are interrelated and correlated?
We need a reward and recognition plan for when people do well.
How are we going to reward them. How do we reward our champions,
our black belts, our green belts, our white belts?
How do we reward individual contributors that steps out of their lucrative well-defined career
to pick up a leadership role for the company in this newfangled thing called Six Sigma?
If they're successful, what are we going to do for them?
They need to have the answer to the question, what's in it for me?
We need a rewards plan. How are they going to be rewarded?
What are they going to be rewarded? See, that's a little different than recognize.
Project planning. How and when are projects identified, selected, and so on?
We need a retention plan for our key players.
Hey, once they got that knowledge how do you stop them from leaving the company?
If you don't take care of them, they’re gone.
So, how are you going to retain a lot of these key players?
So, those are the ten fundamental plans that must be in place.
Now, very briefly. I’ll fold this over.
Here are the planning elements. I’ll use metrics, as an example.
Our planning needs to consider, how are we going to define the metrics?
How do we define our metrics?
How do we document the way those metrics are calculated?
For example, I once discovered in one company, after we got the rollout going.
That there was about six different ways that the moving average was being calculated,
for one of the key operations metrics.
So, everybody kept turning in different results.
That's because we didn't have the method of calculation documented
for the key metrics that were going to be used.
So, you got to define what the metrics are. You gotta document them
on how they're calculated, and so on. Then we have to execute those metrics.
How are they executed? How are they implemented into the organization?
Are they implemented with learning curves and so on?
What's their goals? Is there a goal aligned with them?
Then, how are those metrics tracked and reported?
That's so very key. Is it reported weekly, quarterly, monthly, biannually, semiannually, etc.
And finally, how do we validate
not only the performance of those metrics, the validity and reliability of those metrics?
Do the metrics measure, what they purport to measure?
See there's a lot of things to consider.
A lot of planning elements that need to be addressed in a metrics plan.
And we will talk about these others as well.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.